将错误定位到程序的一小部分的好方法
A great way to localize bugs to a tiny part of your program
是渐进式发展。
is incremental development.
这意味着你只构建了一点程序
That means you're building only a little bit of your program
在你继续之前，一次彻底地测试一下。
at a time and testing that bit thoroughly before you move on.
因为这样当你发现一个虫子，
Because that way when you discover a bug,
很有可能是这个角色
it's very likely to be in the part
你只是在写而不是在任何地方
that you just wrote rather than anywhere
在你可能写过的一大堆代码中。
in the huge pile of code that you might have written.
所以我们的测试课讨论了两种技术
So our class on testing talked about two techniques
这确实有助于增量调试。
that really help with incremental debugging.
一是单元测试。
One is unit testing.
当你单独测试一个模块时，
When you test a module in isolation,
你可以确信你发现的任何错误都在那个单元中
you can be confident that any bug you find is in that unit
或者在测试用例中。
or maybe in the test cases themselves.
但它的代码量较小。
But it's a smaller amount of code.
另一个是回归测试。
Another is regression testing.
当你在一个大系统中添加新功能时，
When you're adding a new feature to a big system,
尽可能频繁地运行回归测试套件。
run the regression test suite as often as you can.
如果测试失败，那么错误可能是
If a test fails, the bug is probably
在你最近修改的代码中。
in the code you just changed very recently.
你也可以通过更好的软件设计来定位错误。
You can also localize bugs by better software designs.
这里有两个关键原则。
There are sort of two key principles here.
一是模块化。
One is modularity.
这意味着把一个系统分成几个小部件
That means dividing a system up into small components
或模块，每个模块都可以设计、实现、测试
or modules, each of which can be designed, implemented, tested
分别论证和重复使用
and reasoned about, and re-used separately
从系统的其他部分。
from the rest of the system.
模块化系统的反面是单片系统。
The opposite of a modular system is a monolithic system.
所以想想，比如，写下你所有的代码
So think about, for example, writing all of your code
在一个单一的，巨大的函数中。
in a single, giant function.
太大了。
That's big.
所有的碎片都被缠住了
It's got all of its pieces tangled up
相互依赖。
and dependent on each other.
没有办法单独分离和测试
And there's no way to individually separate and test
巨大功能的一小部分。
small pieces of that giant function.
所以你真的应该把你的计划搞砸
So you should really aim to break your programs up
分成更小的部分，更小的函数和类。
into much smaller pieces, small functions and classes.
这将使它更加模块化。
That will make it more modular.
这里的第二个关键思想是模块化，
The second key idea here, which is related to modularity,
一旦有了模块，就可以封装它们。
is once you have modules, you can encapsulate them.
所以你可以在他们周围筑墙--
So that means you can build walls around them--
这就是名字的由来，
and that's where the name comes from,
把它想象成硬壳或胶囊--
think of it like a hard shell or a capsule--
使模块负责
so that the module is responsible
因为它自己的内在行为。
for its own internal behavior.
系统的其他部分不会威胁到它的完整性。
And other parts of the system can't threaten its integrity.
你不能威胁模块里面的东西。
You can't threaten what's inside that module.
所以像Java这样的语言提供了访问控制，
So languages like Java give you access control,
关键字，如public、private和protected，
keywords like public and private and protected,
让你控制能见度
that let you control the visibility
以及模块中变量和方法的可访问性。
and accessibility of variables and methods in a module.
任何代码都可以访问公共变量或方法。
Public variable or method can be accessed by any code.
但是私有变量或方法只能
But a private variable or method can only
由同一类中的代码访问。
be accessed by code in the same class.
所以在太空舱里面。
So that's inside the capsule.
尽量保密，
Keeping things private as much as possible,
尤其是变量，限制了可能无意中
especially variables, limits the code that could inadvertently
引起虫子。
cause bugs.
这意味着如果这个变量值——如果一个私有变量
It means if that variable value-- if a private variable's
值是错误的，那么您应该查找错误
value is wrong, then you should look for the bug just
在这个班里。
inside this class.
不可能是别的原因造成的。
It can't be caused by somewhere else.
现在，另一种封装--
Now, another kind of encapsulation--
这就是模块的封装。
so that's encapsulation with respect to modules.
但可变范围是另一种。
But variable scope is another kind.
所以变量的作用域是程序文本的一部分
So the scope of a variable is the part of the program text
定义变量的位置
over which that variable is defined
从某种意义上说，表达式和语句可以引用它，
in the sense that expressions and statements can refer to it,
会读会写。
can read and write it.
方法参数的范围是该方法的主体。
The scope of a method parameter is the body of that method.
好吗？
All right?
它只能在方法的主体中有意义。
It can only have meaning inside the body of that method.
在Java中，局部变量作用域从其声明运行
In Java, a local variable scope runs from its declaration
到下一个右大括号。
to the next closing curly brace.
过了那个大括号，那个变量就没有意义了。
Past that curly brace, that variable no longer has meaning.
实际上，Java会给您一个编译错误
And in fact, Java will give you a compile error
如果你想用这个变量。
if you try to use that variable.
使变量作用域尽可能小
Keeping variable scopes as small as possible
是封装中一个非常重要的原则
is a very important principle in encapsulation
因为这样很容易推断
because it makes it easy to reason about where
程序中可能有错误。
a bug might be in the program.
如果变量值错误，则
If the variable value is wrong, the only place
它可能是在那个范围内的某个地方搞砸的。
it could have been screwed up is somewhere in that scope.
所以如果它的作用域很小，那么代码就会少很多
So if its scope is small, you have a lot less code
为了找出错误你必须学习。
that you have to study in order to find the error.
例如，假设有一个这样的循环
So for example, suppose you have a loop like this
从0开始一个整数变量i并运行
that starts an integer variable i at 0 and runs
直到它达到100并递增
until it reaches 100 and increments it
每一次循环。
each time around the loop.
在这个循环中，你做了很多事情。
And inside that loop, you're doing a number of things.
但是你也叫这个方法做一些事情。
But you're also calling this method do some things.
现在，你发现你有一个虫子
Now, you discover you have a bug where
这个循环永远在运行。
this loop is running forever.
所以我从来没有达到100甚至
So i never actually reaches 100 even
尽管看起来我们每次都在增加。
though it looks like we're incrementing it each time.
所以在某个地方，有人在改变我。
So somewhere, somebody else is changing i.
不仅仅是这部分循环改变了我。
It's not just this part of the loop that is changing i.
问题是，在哪里？
The question is, where?
现在，如果我被声明为全局变量--
Now, if i were declared as a global variable--
我们讨论过全局变量
we've talked about global variables
在之前的阅读中。
in a previous reading.
全局变量是公共的。
Global variables are public.
他们可以从任何地方进入。
They can be accessed from anywhere.
静态意味着只有一个
And static means that there's only one
此变量的实例。
instance of this variable.
但是公共静态变量的问题
But the problem with a public, static variable
全局变量的作用域是
with a global variable is that its scope
是整个程序。
is the entire program.
它可以在程序中的任何地方更改，
It can be changed anywhere in your program,
不仅在这个循环中，而且在这个文件的其他地方
not just inside this loop, but somewhere else in this file
或者是完全不同的文件。
or in a completely different file.
但是如果我被声明为一个局部变量
But if i is instead declared as a local variable
范围很窄，尤其是，
with a narrow scope like this-- particularly,
注意这里的区别是我们确实做到了
notice the difference here is that we have actually made this
变成我的宣言而不是我的任务
into a declaration of i instead of just an assignment of i
把类型放在这里——这个声明
by putting the type here-- this declaration of i
意思是现在我是一个局部变量，其作用域运行
means that now i is a local variable whose scope runs
直到下一个右大括号--匹配的右括号
until the next closing curly brace-- the matching closing
我应该说是花括号。
curly brace, I should say.
所以我唯一可以改变的地方
So the only place where i could possibly be changed
在这里面是为了陈述--事实上，
is inside this for statement-- in fact,
只有在这些地方，这些点-点-点的代码位
only in these places, these dot-dot-dot bits of code
我忽略了。
that I've omitted.
会不会是在身体里做一些事情的方法？
Could it be in the body of the do some things method?
不，因为那是在别的地方实现的
No, because that's implemented somewhere else
不在该变量范围内的代码。
in this code that is not in the scope of this variable.
所以它不能改变我。
So it can't actually change i.
它无法访问或更改此局部变量。
It can't access or change this local variable.
这样就大大降低了风险
So that substantially reduces the risk
我们不小心改变了这个变量
that we are accidentally changing this variable
在错误的地方。
in the wrong place.
最小化变量范围
Minimizing the scope of variables
是一个非常强大的缺陷定位实践。
is a very powerful practice for bug localization.
下面是一些对Java有用的规则
So here's a couple of rules that are useful for Java
使变量的范围最小化。
for minimizing the scope of variables.
一个是你应该总是声明一个循环变量。
One is you should always declare a loop variable.
当你在写for循环时
When you're writing a for loop, you
应该在for循环的初始值设定项中声明循环变量。
should declare the loop variable in the for loop's initializer.
所以与其在循环之上的某个地方声明我
So rather than declaring i somewhere above the loop, which
意味着它的作用域也将包括循环
means that its scope will include the loop as well
作为循环后的一些代码，您应该
as some code after the loop, you should instead
一开始就声明
declare it right there at the beginning
所以它的范围仅限于for循环，
so that its scope is limited to just the for loop,
只是for循环的主体。
just the body of the for loop.
另一个规则是只在您第一次
Another rule is declaring a variable only when you first
需要它。
need it.
这与for循环规则有关。
And this is related to the for loop rule.
然后，把它放在最里面的卷发里
And then, push it down inside the innermost curly
你可以用支撑块。
brace block that you can.
不要声明所有变量
Don't declare all of your variables
在函数开始时。
at the start of the function.
这使得他们的范围不必要地大。
It makes their scopes unnecessarily large.
一开始需要就申报
Declare them as soon as you start needing them
在最里面的花括号里
and in the innermost curly brace block
你能逃脱的。
that you can get away with.
现在，我应该注意到Java和Java之间的区别
Now, I should note here there is a difference between Java
以及其他语言，如Python和JavaScript。
and other languages like Python and JavaScript.
许多语言没有静态类型
Many of those languages that don't have static type
声明，变量的范围
declarations, the scope of the variable
通常是整个函数。
is normally the entire function anyway.
所以不能使用
So you can't restrict the scope of the variable using
这样的花括号。
curly braces in this way.
第三个原则是避免全局变量
And the third principle is just avoid global variables
完全是。
entirely.
它们是一个非常糟糕的主意，特别是作为程序
They are a very bad idea, especially as programs
变大，因为当你有一个涉及
get large, because when you have a bug that involves
全局变量，现在必须搜索整个程序
a global variable, you now have to search the entire program
找出程序的哪个部分
to figure out what part of the program
可能造成了这么大的损失。
might have caused that big.
全局变量常常被不明智地用作快捷方式
Global variables are often unwisely used as a shortcut
在程序的几个部分中提供参数。
to provide a parameter in several parts of your program.
但最好把这个参数
But it's a much better idea just to pass that parameter
在需要它的代码中
into the code that needs it rather than putting it
在全球范围内，它有可能无意中
in the global space where it is at risk of being inadvertently
重新分配。
reassigned.